Gurlal Singh

IT TECHNICIAN

Kent, WA 98032 | C: 206-380-4807 | E: gmworkgroup9@gmail.com

Summary

Pragmatic and methodical professional well versed in IT detailing work, team leadership and customer satisfaction. 2+ years of customer service and interacting with C-Level Executives. First-hand experience in product knowledge, quality systems, hardware testing, logistic technician, process improvement and cost saving initiatives. Great attention to detail and organizational skills. Strong ability to work with others and gain trust while implementing independent judgment.

Skills

SOFT

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Adaptability
- · Problem Solving
- Interpersonal Skills
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Adept in Technology

- Attention to Detail and Creativity
- Cross-Functional Teams

HARD

- Hardware Diagnostics
- Mentoring & Staff Development
- Hardware Replacement /Upgrade
- Application Install & Configuration Server Support & Configuration
- Collecting Data & Information, Developing Objectives
 & Strategies
- Help Desk Assistance and Quality Management Systems.

Experience

SERVICE DESK SPECIALIST | 01/2020 to 03/2020

Valley Medical Center - Renton, WA

- Responded to 35 individual tickets every week to provide end-user support on Computer Hardware and software.
- Documented repair processes and helped streamline procedures for future technical support actions.
- Responded to assistance requests from users and directed individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks and directed to the other IT department depending upon the nature of the ticket.
- Collaborated with support team to assist client stakeholders with emergent technical issues and develop effective solutions.
- Consistently responded to customer service emails within standard window for optimal response.
- Responded to support tickets within SLA to improve customer service.

- Managing 10 A+ Certified Service Technicians in several departments who performs various tasks. Keep Track of Profit
 / Loss/ Labor/ GP and perform required actions for profit and reliability and builds motivation for workers and
 coworker.
- Planning and executing technical projects in store.
- Monitored employee work levels and optimized performance with strategic approaches.
- Expert with ticketing system Tier 2 support.
- Aided with Remote Net Ops Team and Admins for store system security installation, configurations and updates.
- Executing in store level ticketing system on Management Level Tier III keeping track of technicians work and make improvements which lead to Profit /Loss of Department.
- Diagnosing and Troubleshooting Inkjet and Laser Printers Configuring and Managing Network Printer Services.
- Managing servers' racks and managing wires and basic installation and configurations with Net Ops team and admins
- Maintained relationship with other department for their IT, Administrative, clerical needs.

A+ COMPUTER TECHNICIAN | 04/2017 to 12/2018

Fry's Electronics Inc. - Renton, WA

- Day to Day helping Over the counter customers as well as handling on call support.
- Supported employees and customers with advanced troubleshooting on service tickets.
- Identified hardware issues caused by component failures using approved diagnostic tools.
- Configured computers to network drivers and connected to printers and other peripheral equipment.
- Disassembled computer systems to troubleshoot and resolve hardware issues.
- Upgraded laptops/desktops, improving speed and performance.
- Backed up data for customers as well as store level and helping alleviate lost information following malware incident.
- Conferred with vendors to obtain replacement hardware or software and escalate more complex concerns.
- Explained technology-related details in easy-to-understand terms to individuals from all walks of life and in various
 job positions.

CUSTOMER RELATIONSHIP OFFICER | 07/2016 to 11/2016

Bharti Airtel - Jalandhar, Punjab, INDIA

- Focused on the interaction between computer systems, communication methods, sales, and devices. Oversaw the installation and maintenance of systems, including their repairs and testing.
- Offered and negotiated with customer about products Signed up customers for services.
- Service and maintained current sales of customer and escalates with ticketing systems.
- Ensured full customer satisfaction and service experience Provided onsite support and installation of network products.

Education and Training

Lyallpur Khalsa College - Punjab, INDIA | Bachelor of Science

Computer Application, 04/2016

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- www.gsworkgroup.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/gsworkgroup9/

Certifications

- CompTIA Network+
- Microsoft Technology Associate